welcome back to another kdenlive video
欢迎回到另一段Kdenlive视频
tutorial the free video editing software
免费视频编辑软件教程
kdenlive
克登利夫
in this video we're going to be learning
在这段视频中 我们将学习
how to shorten a video clip so maybe he
如何缩短视频片段 这样他可能会
recorded something on your phone and
在你的手机上录下了一些东西
it's like five minutes long and you only
就像五分钟那么长 只有你
want to share a 30-second portion of it
我想分享一段30秒的内容
this will be a great way to learn how to
这将是一个学习如何
do that and also it's going to teach us
做到这一点 也会教会我们
and get us familiar with using this
让我们熟悉一下如何使用这个
interface and using some of the
接口 并使用一些
different tools that kdenlive has to
Kdenlive必须使用的不同工具
offer so first we're gonna drag in a
所以首先我们要拉来一个
video clip I'll go to my downloads I
视频剪辑我会去我的下载网站
have this video clip here this cyclists
这里有这个视频剪辑这个自行车手
getting on a bicycle so I just
骑上自行车 所以我就
left-click and drag it into my projects
左键单击并将其拖动到我的项目中
bin and from there then I can drag it
然后从那里我可以把它拖出来
down to my timeline we can only work
按照我的时间表 我们只能工作
with things in our timeline that are
在我们的时间线上的事情是
already in our project bin so here we
已经在我们的项目箱里了 所以我们在这里
can watch the video right now if I click
如果我点击 我现在就可以观看视频
play we can see what the video looks
播放我们可以看到视频是什么样子的
like we're just kind of monitoring this
就像我们只是在监视这件事
clip but we're not really looking at our
剪辑 但我们并没有真正看到我们的
project so if we were to render out or
项目 所以如果我们要渲染或
try and save this video it would just
试着保存这段视频 它只会
come out black because if we click here
显示为黑色 因为如果我们点击此处
on our project monitor down here we have
在我们的项目监控器上 我们有
no video no audio nothing happening in
没有视频 没有音频 什么都没有发生
our project we just have something we
我们的项目我们只是有一些东西
just have a clip potentially we can work
只要有一个片段 我们就可以工作
with so since we do want to work with
既然我们确实想要使用
this clip let's drag it into our
这个片段让我们把它拖到我们的
timeline so we'll left-click drag it
时间线 所以我们将左键单击并拖动它
down and just throw it in the timeline
然后把它放在时间线上
the timeline starts at 0 if you look
如果你看一下 时间线从0开始
there's this white playhead here we can
这里有一个白色的弹头 我们可以
actually click if we click up here in
如果我们点击此处 实际点击
this gray area we can click and see
这是我们可以点击查看的灰色区域
different parts of this video so right
这段视频的不同部分是如此的正确
here we're looking at the video if we go
这是我们在看录像 如果我们去
back here we're just seeing black so we
回到这里 我们只看到黑色 所以我们
want to make sure our video is at the
想要确保我们的视频在
very beginning of our project so do that
我们的项目一开始就这么做
we'll left-click and drag all the way to
我们将左键单击并一直拖动到
the start so now when we go back to 0 0
现在开始 当我们回到0的时候
we see the very first frame of our video
我们看到了视频的第一帧
is it's not black anymore like it was
它不再像以前那样黑了
it's actually showing our video which is
它实际上正在播放我们的视频
good and if we hit play we can play
很好 如果我们按下Play 我们就可以玩了
through and watch and see what this
看完了 看看这是什么
looks like so maybe this video is way
看起来是这样 所以这段视频可能是
too long for us which really it isn't
对我们来说太长了 其实不是
it's only about less than 10 seconds
大概只有不到10秒
long but if we if we think it's too long
很长 但如果我们觉得太长了
we want to make it shorter we can cut
我们想让它变短 我们可以剪掉
and make it shorter to do that we'll hit
让它变得更短 我们会击中
the X key so we hit the X key on our
按下X键 这样我们就可以在我们的
keyboard and we get this nice
键盘和我们得到的这个很好
cutting scissor cursor option another
剪切剪刀光标选项另一种
way we can do it I'm gonna hit s to go
我们能做到的 我要打S走
back to what we're before so we can move
回到我们以前的样子 这样我们才能搬家
us around we can hit the scissor tool
我们周围的人可以点击剪刀工具
here we just click on it and we get this
在这里 我们只需点击它 我们就会得到这个
scissor tool to cut so I'm gonna hit
剪下的剪刀 所以我要打
left-click on my clip and I'll cut and
左键单击我的剪辑 我将剪切并
I'll go back to my selection tool and we
我会回到我的选择工具 然后我们
can see we have two video clips now we
可以看到我们现在有两个视频剪辑
have one that's our first one we have
有一个 这是我们的第一个
our second one so that's a way we can we
我们的第二个 所以这是我们可以
maybe we want to use this one somewhere
也许我们想在什么地方用这个
else or if we don't we can just hit the
否则 如果我们不这样做 我们就可以直接
Delete key while it's selected and it'll
选中时删除关键点 它将
be gone so now our video is only half as
所以现在我们的视频只有一半
long and yeah so we've just shortened
又长又好 所以我们刚刚缩短了
this video basically by half it's still
这个视频基本上减半了它仍然是
playing at the same speed so we go to
以相同的速度演奏 所以我们去了
play we can see it's still playing at
播放我们可以看到它仍在播放
the same speed that it was this little
同样的速度 它是这么小的
blue thing that I just moved by the way
顺便说一句 我刚搬了个蓝色的东西
we see right here this is the extent of
我们在这里看到 这是
our video so this blue line shows us how
我们的视频 这条蓝线向我们展示了
long our video project will be when we
长久以来 我们的视频项目将在我们
go to render we have an option we can
转到渲染 我们有一个选项 我们可以
just render our whole every video clip
只需呈现我们所有的视频片段
that's in our timeline as one option we
这是我们的时间表中的一个选择 我们
can also say only render to the extents
也可以说只渲染到一定程度
of this of this blue bar so if we want
这条蓝色的条 所以如果我们想
our video to only be 20 seconds long we
我们的视频只有20秒长
would just set it right here at 20
只会把它设定在这里20
seconds then our video would stop when
几秒后 我们的视频将在以下时间停止
it got to 20 seconds but we'll use that
它有20秒 但我们将使用它
later it won't really apply to us in
稍后 它将不会真正适用于我们
this case that's one thought you know
这个案子 你知道的 这是一个想法
because when you first start that's it
因为当你第一次开始的时候就是这样
gets in the way sometimes when you're
有时你会遇到麻烦 因为
trying to move the playhead you
试着移动你的播放头
accidentally move this blue thing
不小心把这个蓝色的东西
instead so that's why I bring that up
相反 这就是我提出这一点的原因
also with this video so we're on video
还有这段视频 所以我们在视频中
track 1 if we want to zoom in and kind
音轨1 如果我们想要放大和亲切
of see and make a more detailed cut we
看到并做出更详细的裁剪 我们
can actually come down here to the
实际上可以来到这里的
bottom right and we'll click and drag
右下角 我们将单击并拖动
this little square and we can it'll
这个小方块 我们可以 它会
resize the way we're looking at this
调整我们看待这件事的方式
timeline so it'll kind of zoom in on
时间线 所以它会放大
time it doesn't change the size of the
时间不会改变
video actually in our project it doesn't
视频实际上在我们的项目中并不存在
change how fast it plays or how long the
更改播放速度或播放时间
duration of it but it helps us get a
它的持续时间 但它帮助我们获得
much more granular look now we can drag
现在我们可以拖动更细粒度的外观
and pan through and kind of see frame by
平移到另一边 有点像是在看边框
frame what's happening in this video
框住这段视频中正在发生的事情
clip whereas before it was so small it
夹子 而在它还这么小之前
would have been hard to cut very
会很难砍掉
precisely
准确地说
so that's how that works so we'll zoom
这就是它的工作原理 所以我们将缩放
in here and sometimes if you have like a
在这里 有时如果你有一个
two hour video project you know you
两个小时的视频项目你了解你自己
don't want to you know if one pixel a
我不想让你知道如果一个像素
fraction of an inch on your screen will
在你的屏幕上一英寸的小部分将
mean the difference between you know
意思是你知道的
five minutes of cutting video footage of
五分钟的剪辑视频片段
it so you need to zoom in to get a very
所以你需要放大才能得到一个非常清晰的
accurate look so yeah so we've cut this
看起来很准确 所以我们剪掉了这个
we've cut this video let's let's go
我们已经剪下了这段视频 我们走吧
through that one more time how to do
再通过那一次怎么办？
that I'll show you a third way if we go
如果我们去的话我会告诉你第三条路
up to tool and select this razor tool
上至工具并选择此剃须刀工具
that's how we get this it's this turns
这就是我们得到这一切的方式这就是这一切
to the scissor icon and then we can then
到剪刀图标 然后我们就可以
cut cut cut as many times as we've left
剪多少次我们就剪多少次
click it'll cut you can then create a
点击它 你就可以创建一个
separate clip and then we go back to
分开剪辑 然后我们回到
this tool and go to our selection tool
此工具并转到我们的选择工具
and then we can actually select these
然后我们实际上可以选择这些
videos and move them around we can
视频和移动它们 我们可以
select one and delete it if we want just
选择一个并删除它 如果我们只想
the Delete key
Delete键
so what everyone has a red box around it
所以每个人周围都有一个红色的盒子
that's what's selected so now we've
这就是我们所选择的 所以现在我们已经
really shortened this video a lot and
我把这段视频缩短了很多
you see this is up here on video track
你看 这是上面的录像带
two which doesn't matter it'll still
两个无关紧要的 还是
play correctly when we play through but
当我们玩完的时候正确地玩 但是
for for all intents and purposes I was
因为无论出于何种意图和目的 我都
our down play we should just keep
我们的低调 我们应该继续
everything in the same track at least
至少所有事情都在同一条轨道上
for this video to avoid confusion so
这个视频为了避免混淆 所以
everything's on video track one and
一切都在第一首录像带上
there's no audio with this video it's
这段视频没有音频 它是
completely silent if it had audio it
如果它有音频 则完全静音
would be playing along with the video
会和视频一起播放
and we're walk out we'll do it we'll
我们走出去 我们会做的 我们会的
play out the audio in the next video as
将下一个视频中的音频播放为
well we can add music if we just bring
好吧 我们可以加音乐 如果我们只是带来
music in like if I want to bring an
音乐就像如果我想带一个
audio file into here I can go find some
音频文件放到这里我可以去找一些
audio on my computer left click and drag
我的电脑上的音频左键单击并拖动
it in and we'll drag it down to the
然后我们会把它拖到
timeline and then it will play audio
时间线 然后它将播放音频
along with our video footage it'll
与我们的视频片段一起
actually play there that sound is the
实际上在那里播放的声音是
audio file playing so I'm going to
播放音频文件 所以我要
render this out very quickly in fact I'm
非常快地呈现出来 事实上 我是
just going to drag this audio to here
我要把这段音频拖到这里
will delete this last clip make a nice
我会删除这最后一个剪辑使一个很好
short one I'll shrink the audio down to
短一点 我会把音频缩小到
about there and let's render this out so
大概在那里 让我们把它渲染成这样
to render to save our video if this is
来渲染以保存我们的视频 如果这是
all we want to do is cut our video and
我们要做的就是剪下我们的视频
then upload it to Facebook or YouTube or
然后上传到Facebook或YouTube或
somewhere we'll just click on render
在某个位置 我们只需点击Render
well first of all I'll show you kind of
好的 首先我会给你们展示一种
the wrong way to do it I guess if you go
如果你走了 我想这是错误的做法
to file save that's just gonna save a
来保存文件 这只会节省一个
kdenlive project
Kdenlive项目
so we can we can do this we can save
所以我们可以我们可以做到这一点我们可以拯救
under documents we can call it my video
在文件中 我们可以称之为我的视频
and hit save and that will just save it
然后点击保存 这样就可以保存它
under it'll be a dot kdenlive file which
它的下面将是一个.kdenlive文件 它
is good if we ever want to come back in
如果我们还想再回来的话
and define tweak and replace the audio
并定义调整和替换音频
or make changes to this video project we
或对此视频项目进行更改 我们
can do that but that video will not be
可以这样做 但那段视频不会
that that's just going to be a video
那只会是一段视频
video project file
视频项目文件
we can't upload the that this to YouTube
我们不能把这个上传到YouTube上
or or send it email it to a friend or
或将其通过电子邮件发送给朋友或
something so to actually render out a
这样的东西实际上呈现出
video we click on render not save by
我们点击渲染而不是保存方式的视频
default
默认设置
well first we want to do is choose out
首先 我们要做的就是选择
choose our output file so where do we
选择我们的输出文件 那么我们应该在哪里
want to render it to click these dots
我想要渲染它以单击这些点
here I'm gonna do mine to the desktop
在这里 我将在桌面上做我的工作
and we'll just call it test we'll hit
我们就叫它测试吧 我们会打
save so the very first thing it has an
保存 这样它第一件事就是有一个
automatic default as this web M which
自动默认为此Web M 其中
will be which would work it's a video
会是哪一个行得通？这是一段视频
format not everyone not all players can
格式不是每个人都能 也不是所有玩家都能
play that mp4 is a pretty widely known
播放MP4是一个广为人知的
pretty common one it's a good one to use
很常见的 很好用的
if you're uploading to YouTube or
如果您正在上传到YouTube或
Facebook if it's a final video so I'm
脸书 如果这是最终的视频 所以我
also at mp4 there's all these different
同样在MP4上 有所有这些不同的
options for if we want to export the
如果我们想要导出
audio only we can export different
只有我们可以输出不同的音频
lossless formats we can just export an
无损格式 我们只需将
image sequence but for this we'll just
图像序列 但对于此 我们只需
click mp4 choose your output location
点击MP4选择您的输出位置
like we did and then go ahead and save
就像我们做的那样 然后继续前进 拯救
and then we'll hit render Oh before that
然后我们会在那之前点击Render哦
I just want to show you right now it's
我现在只想告诉你这是
rendering the full project which means
呈现完整的项目 这意味着
it's gonna render the extent of all
它将呈现出所有的
video clips that we've added but that
我们添加的视频剪辑 但
blue thing I was talking about there's
蓝色的东西 我说的是
this selected zone if we if we do
如果我们这样做 这个选定的区域
selected zone it'll only render the part
选定区域它将仅渲染该部分
that we have selected in our selected
我们在我们的选择中选择
zone that'll make sense more on the
更有意义的区域
teacher we'll play with that a little
老师 我们来玩玩这个
bit so make sure this says full project
所以请确保这是完整的项目
and click render to file and this is
然后单击渲染到文件 这是
rendering out very quickly because it's
渲染速度非常快 因为它
only what a two second three second long
只有2秒3秒那么长
video and now it's done rendering so we
视频 现在它已经完成渲染 所以我们
can hit close here we can minimize and
可以靠近这里 我们可以最大限度地减少
go to the desktop and we can see this
转到桌面 我们可以看到以下内容
video that we've created
我们制作的视频
that's it just keep looping over and
就是这样 继续循环 然后
over again just a short little clip this
再来一小段这个短片
guy getting on his bike
一个骑着自行车的家伙
and it's a little sound playing in the
这是一个小小的声音在播放
background so I hope you've enjoyed this
所以我希望你喜欢这篇文章
video I hope you found it informative go
我希望你觉得这个视频很有见地
ahead and like and subscribe check out
提前点赞并订阅退房
my other tutorials on kdenlive and other
我在kdenlive上的其他教程和其他
software and I'll catch you in the next
软件 我会在下一个
video
视频